linkvendor.de 2019-06-24

# Privacy Statement | Searchmetrics

We provide information on the collection of personal information when using our website below. Personal data is any data that personally refers to you, so for example, name, address, email addresses, user behaviour. We have taken extensive technical and operational precautions to protect your data from accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Our safety procedures are regularly checked and adapted with the latest technological advancements. Items starting with number 8 below that refer to the website are marked with W and those that refer to our Suite are marked with S. Items 1 through 7 refer to the website and the Searchmetrics Suite.

#### 1 Those responsible for data processing

Responsible parties in accordance with Article 4 Paragraph 7 EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is Searchmetrics GmbH, Greifswalder Straße 212, 10405 Berlin, Tel: 030/ 322 95 35 – 0 Email address: data.protection@searchmetrics.com

#### 2 Contact option for the data protection officer

You can contact our data protection officer at SSchmidbauer@intersoft-consulting.de or at our postal address with the heading “the data protection officer”.]

#### 3 Your rights

You have the following rights towards us regarding your personal data: 3.1 General rights You have a right to access, rectification, cancellation, restriction of processing, objection to processing and data transferability. If a processing is based on your consent, you have the right to revoke this consent with effect for the future.

##### 3.2 Rights in data processing according to the legitimate interest

You have the right, pursuant to Art. 21 Paragraph 1 GDPR, for reasons arising from your particular situation, to object at any time to the processing of personal data relating to you on the basis of Art. 6 Paragraph 1e GDPR (data processing in the public interest) or on the basis of Article 6 paragraph1f GDPR (data processing to safeguard a legitimate interest), including profiling based on this provision based on these provisions. In the event of your objection, we will no longer process your personal data unless we can show compelling grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

##### 3.3 Rights related to direct advertising

If we process your personal data in order to carry out direct advertising, you have the right pursuant to Art. 21 Paragraph 2 GDPR to object at any time to the processing of personal data concerning you for the purpose of such advertising, including profiling in so far as it is related to such direct marketing. In the event of your objection to processing for direct marketing purposes, we will no longer process your personal data for these purposes

##### 3.4 The right of appeal to a supervisory authority

You also have the right to lodge a complaint to a data protection supervisory authority concerning our processing of your personal data. 4 Collection of personal data when visiting our website If you use the website for information purposes only, i.e. if you do not register or otherwise provide us with information, we only collect the personal data that your browser transmits to our server. If you wish to view our website, we collect the following data, which are technically necessary for us to display our website to you and to guarantee stability and security. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Paragraph 1f GDPR:

IP address, date and time of the request, time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT), content of the request (specific page), access status/HTTP status code, amount of data transferred in each case, website from which the request comes, browser, operating system, and its interface, language and version of the browser software, Dwell time, click path / actions / interactions with the website.

Website information:

  * URL – the URL of the page viewed by a user
  * Title – the page title of the page viewed by a user
  * Visiting Time – How long a user was on the site and how long on each subpage
  * Referrer – From which source a user comes to the website

Browser information:

  * Browser – Name of the browser used
  * Viewport – size of the browser window
  * Screen resolution – the screen resolution that the user uses
  * JavaScript – whether the user uses JavaScript or not
  * Operating system – name of the operating system used User information:
  * Location – based on the IP address, which is anonymized by not passing the last octet of the address. The determination of location is thus only approximately possible
  * Language – language of the user, based on the language setting of the browser

#### 5 Contact us by e-mail or through the contact form

When you contact us by e-mail or via a contact form, the data you provide (your e-mail address, and if applicable your name and your telephone number) will be stored by us in order to answer your questions. If we use our contact form to request information that is not required to establish contact, it will always be marked as optional. These details help us answer your inquiry and to improve the processing of your request. This information is provided expressly on a voluntary basis and with your consent, Art. 6 Paragraph1a GDPR. If this includes information on communication channels (e.g. e-mail address, telephone number), you also agree that we may contact you via this communication channel in order to respond to your request. You can of course revoke this consent at any time in the future. We delete the data arising in this context after the storage is no longer necessary or limit the processing if statutory retention obligations exist.

#### 6 Newsletter

##### 6.1 General information

With your consent according to Art. 6 Paragraph 1a GDPR you can subscribe to our newsletter, in which we inform you about our current offers. To register for our newsletter, we use the “double opt-in” procedure. This means that after your registration we will send you an e-mail to the specified e-mail address in which we ask you to confirm that you would like the newsletter to be sent. In addition, we store your IP addresses and the time of registration and confirmation. The purpose of the procedure is to be able to prove your registration and, if necessary, to clarify a possible misuse of your personal data. The only required information for sending the newsletter is your name, surname and email address. The disclosure of further, separately marked data is voluntary and is used to be able to address you personally. After your confirmation we will save your e-mail address for the purpose of sending you the newsletter. The legal basis is Art. 6 Paragraph 1a GDPR. You can revoke your consent to receive the newsletter at any time and unsubscribe from the newsletter. You can declare your revocation by clicking on the link provided in every newsletter e-mail or by sending a contact request to the data protection officer specified above.

##### 6.2 Newsletter tracking

We would like to point out that we evaluate your user behaviour when sending the newsletter. For this analysis, the e-mails sent contain so-called web beacons or tracking pixels, which are stored on our website. For evaluation purposes, we link the above data and web beacons to your e-mail address and an individual ID. With the data obtained in this way, we create a user profile to tailor the newsletter to your individual interests. This means we can record when you read our newsletter, which links you click on in it, and keep track of your personal interests. We link these data with how you use our website. You can object to this tracking at any time by clicking on the separate link provided in each e-mail. The information is stored for as long as you have subscribed to the newsletter. After a cancellation we store the data purely statistically and anonymously. Such tracking is also not possible if you have deactivated the display of images in your e-mail program by default. In this case the newsletter will not be displayed completely and you may not be able to use all functions. If you display the images manually, the above-mentioned tracking will occur.

#### 7 Registration and use of the portal (S)

You have the possibility to register with us and create a customer account. For registration we collect and store the following data from you: – First name – Last name – Email (username) – Password – Country We use the “double opt-in” procedure for registration, i.e. your registration is not complete until you have confirmed your registration via a confirmation email sent to you for this purpose by clicking on the link contained therein. It is obligatory to provide the aforementioned data; all further information can be provided voluntarily by using our portal. After successful registration, you will receive a personal, password-protected access and you can view and manage the data you have provided. Registration is voluntary, but may be a prerequisite for using our services. If you use our portal, we store any data from you that is necessary for the fulfilment of the contract, potentially along with information on the method of payment, until you delete your access with final effect. Furthermore, we will store the optional data provided by you for the duration of your use the of portal, unless you delete it prior to this. You can manage and change all information in the protected customer area. The legal basis is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 a, b and f GDPR.

#### 8 Online orders – Shop (W)

When you place an online order on our website, we collect the various data required to conclude the contract. The legal basis is the conclusion and execution of a contract in accordance with Art. 6 Paragraph 1b GDPR. The data will be stored for the duration of the contract and in accordance with legal obligations. For payment processing, we use various payment service providers who are always identified and who directly accept your entries and are therefore recipients of your personal data collected in connection with the payment transaction. The legal basis for the involvement of payment service providers is the execution of the contract in accordance with Art. 6 Paragraph 1b GDPR. The storage for the purpose of payment takes place for the duration of the payment processing.

#### 9 Participation in competitions (W)

When you participate in sweepstakes, we collect the data necessary to conduct the sweepstake. These are usually an individual competition entry (e.g. a comment or a photo), as well as name and contact details. We may pass on your data to our competition partners, e.g. to send you the prize. The processing and transfer of data may vary depending on the competition and is therefore described in detail in the respective conditions of participation. Participation in the competition and the related data collection is of course voluntary. The legal basis for data processing is your consent pursuant to Art. 6 Paragraph 1a GDPR. Your data will be deleted after the end of the competition.

#### 10 Job applications (W)

You can apply to our company electronically, in particular via e-mail or web forms. We will of course use your details exclusively for processing your application and will not pass them on to third parties. Please note that unencrypted e-mails are not transmitted with access protection. You can also apply via our online application portal. Your online application will be forwarded directly to the HR department via an encrypted connection and will of course be treated confidentially. We will of course use your details exclusively for processing your application and will not pass them on to third parties. Further information on data processing within the application procedure can be found in the data protection declaration of our application portal. If you have applied for a specific position and it has already been filled or if we consider you suitable for another position, we would be happy to forward your application within the company. Please let us know if you do not agree to this forwarding. Your personal data will be deleted immediately after completion of the application process or after a maximum of 6 months, unless you have expressly given us your consent to store your data for longer or a contract has been concluded. The legal basis is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 a, b and f GDPR and § 26 BDSG.

#### 11 Use of Social Plugins (W)

This site uses social plugins. These plugins usually collect data from you by default and transmit them to the servers of the respective provider. In order to guarantee the protection of your privacy, we have taken technical measures to ensure that your data cannot be collected by the providers of the respective plugin without your consent. When visiting a page on which the plugins are integrated, these are initially deactivated. Only when you click on the respective symbol are the plugins activated and you thereby give your consent that your data can be transferred to the respective provider. The legal basis for the use of the plugins is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 a and f GDPR. After activation, the plugins also collect personal data such as your IP address and send it to the servers of the respective provider, where it is stored. Furthermore, activated social plugins use a cookie with a unique identifier when connecting to the respective website. This also allows providers to create profiles of your usage behaviour. This also happens if you are not a member of the social network of the respective provider. If you are a member of the social network of the provider and you are logged in to the social network during your visit to this website, your data and information about your visit to this website may be linked to your profile on the social network. We have no influence on the exact extent of the data collected from you by the respective provider. For more information about the scope, type and purpose of data processing and about rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy, please refer to the data protection information of the respective provider of the social network. These can be found at the following addresses:

Facebook:  
We use plugins from the social network facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The link to Facebook’s Privacy Policy can be found here: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>

Twitter:  
We use Twitter social plug-ins, which are operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA (“Twitter”). The link to the privacy policy of Twitter can be found here: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>

Pinterest:  
We use plugins from the Pinterest social network operated by Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, USA (“Pinterest”). The link to Pinterest’s Privacy Policy can be found here: <https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>

#### 12 Use of cookies (W/S)

When using our website, cookies are stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard disk in association with the browser you are using and by which the body which sets the cookie transmits certain information. Cookies cannot run programmes or deliver viruses to your computer. They serve to make our web offer more user-friendly and effective. We also use cookies to identify you for follow-up visits if you have an account with us. Otherwise you would have to log in again for each visit. This website uses the following types of cookies, the scope and functionality of which are explained below:

##### 12.1 Transient Cookies

These cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. These include session cookies, in particular. These store a session ID which assigns the various requests made by your browser during the joint session. This allows your computer to be recognized when you return to the site. Session cookies are deleted when you log out or close the browser.

##### 12.2 Persistent cookies

These cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may vary depending on the cookie. You can delete the cookies in your browser’s security settings at any time.

##### 12.3 Flash cookies

The Flash cookies used are not recorded by your browser, but by your Flash plug-in. We also use HTML5 storage objects that are stored on your mobile device. These objects store the required data independently of your browser and do not have an automatic expiry date. If you do not wish the Flash cookies to be processed, you must install an appropriate add-on, e.g. “Better Privacy” for Mozilla Firefox (<https://addons.mozilla.org/de/firefox/addon/betterprivacy/>) or the Adobe Flash killer cookie for Google Chrome. You can prevent the use of HTML5 storage objects by using private mode in your browser. We also recommend that you regularly delete your cookies and your browser history manually.

##### 12.4 Prevention of cookies

You can configure your browser settings according to your needs and, for example, refuse to accept third-party cookies or all cookies. Please note that you may not be able to use all functions of this website.

##### 12.5 Legal bases and storage period

The legal bases for possible processing of personal data and their storage duration vary and are described in the following sections.

#### 13 Website analysis

For the purpose of analysing and optimising our websites we use various services, which are described below. For example, we can analyze how many users visit our site, which information is most in demand or how users find the offer. Among other things, we collect data about the website from which a person has accessed a website (so-called referrer), which subpages of the website were accessed or how often and for how long a subpage was viewed. This helps us to design and improve our offers in a user-friendly way. The data collected is not used to personally identify individual users. Anonymous or at most pseudonymous data is collected. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Paragraph 1f GDPR.

##### 13.1 Google Analytics (W)

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc, (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). The use includes the Universal Analytics mode. This makes it possible to assign data, sessions and interactions across multiple devices to a pseudonymous user ID and thus analyze a user’s activities across devices. Google Analytics uses cookies, which enable how you use the website to be analysed. As a rule, the cookie-generated data regarding your use of this website will be forwarded to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, your IP address will first be abbreviated by Google within the member states of the European Union or other parties to the agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics is not conflated with other Google data. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage for the website operator. Our legitimate interest in data processing also lies in these purposes. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is § 15 Paragraph 3 TMG (Telemedia Act) and Art. 6 Paragraph 1f GDPR. The data sent by us and linked with cookies are not deleted automatically as we do not collect user identifiers (e.g., user IDs) or promotional IDs, and only aggregated data. For more information on terms of use and data protection, visit <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html> or <https://policies.google.com/?hl=de> You can prevent cookies from being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser; however, we wish to point out that by doing so, you may not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this website. Furthermore, you can prevent the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to the usage of the website (including your IP address) and the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug that is available at the following link <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>. Opt-out cookies prevent future acquisition of your data when you visit this website, if you click on this link: deactivate Google Analytics 

##### 13.2 Matomo (formerly Piwik) (W/S)

This SUITE and Website uses the web analysis service Matomo (formerly Piwik) to analyse and regularly improve the use of our SUITE. We can improve our offer and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal basis for the use of Matomo is Art. 6 Paragraph 1f GDPR.

Cookies are stored on your computer for this evaluation. This SUITE uses Matomo with the extension “AnonymizeIP”. Your IP address is never stored in Matomo and not used for further processing. The Matomo program is an open source project. You can obtain information on data protection from the third-party provider at https://matomo.org/privacy/. Users can activate the DoNotTrack functionality in their web browser if they want to prevent us from gathering any usage data in Matomo.

##### 13.3 Suite analysis (S)

For the purpose of analysing and optimising our SUITE we use various services, which are described below. For example, we can analyze how many users visit our site, which information is most in demand or how users find the offer. Among other things, we collect data about the website from which a person has accessed a website (so-called referrer), which subpages of the website were accessed or how often and for how long a subpage was viewed. This helps us to design and improve our offers in a user-friendly way. Anonymous or at most pseudonymous data is collected. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Paragraph 1f GDPR.

In addition, in order to provide better service to users we analyze how the SUITE is used regarding the modules used and the projects accessed. To archive this, we combine user-IDs and license-IDs from Matomo with registered-user data from our SUITE to archive this. Visitors with the DoNotTrack-flag int their browser are (by design) excluded from this data merger.

##### 13.4 Double Click By Google

Doubleclick by Google is a service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Doubleclick by Google uses cookies to show you advertisements that are relevant to you. Your browser will be assigned a pseudonymous identification number (ID) to check which ads have appeared in your browser and which ads have been viewed. The cookies do not contain any personal information. Using the DoubleClick cookie allows Google and its affiliate websites to serve ads based on previous visits to our or other websites on the Internet. The information generated by the cookies is transmitted by Google for evaluation to a server in the USA and stored there. A transfer of the data by Google to third parties takes place only due to legal regulations or in the context of order data processing. In no case will Google match its data with other data collected by Google. By using our web pages, you agree to the processing of the data collected about you by Google and according to the manner described above, as to the data processing and to the stated purpose. You can prevent the storage of cookies by a setting of your browser software; However, we would like to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all the functions of our web pages in full. You may also prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookies and related to your use of the website as well as the processing of this data by Google by using the following link (<https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en>) download and install the available browser plugin. Alternatively, you can disable the Doubleclick cookies on the Digital Advertising Alliance website at the following link (<http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/>). For more information about privacy and cookies for advertising with DoubleClick, please refer to the Google Privacy Policy, especially the following links: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites> <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=de>

##### 13.5 Using the Remarketing or “Like Audiences” feature of Google Inc. (W)

We use the Remarketing or “Like Audiences” feature of Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”) on our website. This feature has the purpose of analyzing visitor behavior and visitor interests.

Google uses cookies to carry out the analysis of the website usage, which forms the basis for the creation of interest-based advertisements. The cookies are used to record site visits and anonymous data on the use of the website. There is no storage of personal data of visitors to the website. If you visit another website on the Google Display Network, you’ll see ads that are likely to include previously viewed product and information areas.

If necessary, your data will also be transmitted to the USA. There is an adequacy decision by the European Commission for data transfers to the US.

Processing is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO for the legitimate interest in targeting visitors to the Website through advertising by showing personalized, interest-based advertising ads to visitors to the Provider’s website when visiting other websites on the Google Display Network.

You can permanently deactivate the use of cookies by Google by following the link below and downloading and installing the plug-in provided there: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en>

Alternatively, you may opt out of third-party cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative deactivation page at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and implementing the opt-out information listed there.

For more information about Google Remarketing and its privacy policy, please visit: <https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>

##### 13.6 Marketo (W)

(1) We use the services of the company Marketo EMEA Limited to collect statistical data on the use of our web site and to optimize our offerings accordingly, as well as to operate e-mail marketing.

(2) Processing of personal data upon registration If you register for an event, request the newsletter or other information, or otherwise provide us with personal information through a registration form, the registration form will ask you to consent to the processing of your personal information.

(3) Cookies Marketo also uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is transmitted to a server of Marketo (in an EU / EEA country) and stored there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Marketo uses this information to evaluate the use of the website by registered persons and to compile reports on website activity. You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible.

(4) Tracking pixel We point out that Marketo evaluates your user behavior when sending the newsletter or other requested information on our behalf. For this evaluation, the emails sent contain so-called web beacons, also called tracking pixels. These are one-pixel image files that link to our website, allowing us to evaluate your user behavior. With the data obtained in this way, we create a user profile in order to provide you with the newsletter tailored to your interests. In doing so, we record when you read our newsletters, which links you click in and conclude your personal interests. We link this data with actions you have taken on our website. The collected information are stored by Marketo on its server in the EU / EEA. Tracking is not possible if you have disabled the display of images in your e-mail program by default. However, in this case the newsletter will not be displayed completely and you may not be able to use all the features. If you display the images manually, the above mentioned tracking occurs.

(5) You can prevent the storage of cookies and tracking via tracking pixels. You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. You can prevent tracking by disabling the display of images by default in your e-mail program. However, in this case the newsletter will not be displayed completely and you may not be able to use all the features. If you display the images manually, the above tracking is done.

(6) Address of Marketo and URL with their privacy notices: Marketo EMEA Ltd. Cairn House South County Business Park Leopardstown Road Dublin 18 Ireland [legal.marketo.com/vertrauen/legal/datenschutz/](https://documents.marketo.com/toutapp/privacy/)

Opt-out cookies prevent future acquisition of your data when you visit this website, if you click on this link: deactivate Marketo pixel

#### 14 Advertisement (W)

We use cookies for marketing purposes, in order to address our users with interest-fair advertisement. In addition, we use cookies to limit the likelihood of an advertisement being played and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising measures. This information may also be shared with third parties, such as ad networks. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 paragraph 1 a and f GDPR. Direct marketing has a legitimate interest in data processing. You have the right to object at any time to the processing of your data for the purpose of such advertising. In the following, we provide you with opt-out options for the respective services. Alternatively, you can prevent cookies from being set in your browser settings.

##### 14.1 Facebook Pixel, Custom Audiences and Facebook Remarketing

Within our online offer and due to our legitimate interests in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of the online offering, the so-called “Facebook Pixel” of the social network Facebook, which is owned by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, or if you are located in the EU, Facebook Ireland, 4 Grand Canal, Grand Canal Harbor, Dublin 2, Ireland is used. With the help of the Facebook pixel, it is on the one hand possible for Facebook to designate the visitors of our offer as a target group for the presentation of advertisements, the so-called “Facebook ads”. Accordingly, we use the Facebook pixel in order to show our Facebook ads only to Facebook users who are relevant to us as a target group.Opt-out cookies prevent future acquisition of your data when you visit this website, if you click on this link: deactivate Facebook Pixel

Opt-out cookies prevent future acquisition of your data when you visit this website, if you click on this link: deactivate Twitter pixel

Opt-out cookies prevent future acquisition of your data when you visit this website, if you click on this link: deactivate LinkedIn pixel

#### 15 Transmission of data (W/S)

A transfer of your data to third parties does not take place, unless we are legally obliged to do so, or the transfer of data is necessary for the execution of the contractual relationship, or you have previously expressly consented to the transfer of your data. External service providers and partner companies such as online payment providers or the shipping company commissioned with the delivery will only receive your data if this is necessary to process your order. In these cases, the amount of data disclosed is limited to the required minimum. Insofar as our service providers come into contact with your personal data, we ensure in the context of order processing acc. to Art. 28 DSGVO that they comply with the provisions of data protection laws in the same way. Please also note the respective data protection information of the providers. The respective service provider is responsible for the content of external services, whereby we check the compliance of the services with the legal requirements within the scope of reasonableness. It is important to us to process your data within the EU/EEA. However, we may use service providers who process data outside the EU/EEA. In these cases, we ensure that an appropriate level of data protection is established at the recipient prior to the transfer of your personal data. This means that a data protection level comparable to the standards within the EU is achieved via EU standard contracts or an adequacy decision, such as the EU Privacy Shield.

#### 16 Data security (W/S)

Your personal data is securely transmitted by encryption. We use the coding system SSL (Secure Socket Layer). We have taken extensive technical and operational precautions to protect your data from accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Our safety procedures are regularly checked and adapted with the latest technological advancements.

As of August 2018
